Gurukanth Desai
salutes the Shakti family.
Don't dream.
"We've been awake for a long time.."
"Let us sleep for some time more."
'Dreams never come true.'
"There's still night left.."
My father would say always.
"Let the morning come."
But I dreamt.
"We've been awake for a long time.."
"Let us sleep for some time more."
"There's still night left.."
"Let the morning come."
I'll work in Turkey
like Ghanshyam Das.
Which fool will give a
job to a fool like you?
He had gone to
town for an interview.
Ghanshyam Das had taken him.
He has got the job, father.
I got my passport too.
Why's this happening behind my back?
The school results will
be out tomorrow, right?
Have you checked
the results in town?
Have you failed?
Oh, you are trying to
cover the shame with a job.
I've got a job in Turkey. Now
how does a pass or fail matter?
I'll beat you. The whole
village will laugh that..
..the math teacher's son has
failed. You'll never prosper.
Don't curse. He's going abroad.
Oh Mother Bhavani.
- Go to hell.
I can't bear that my
son has failed. Go.
Come on, leave. Come on, move.
Hey congratulations. We've done it.
My stepson is going abroad.
Your stepson is going abroad.
Fall at my feet, you foolish man.
You lousy woman, your
stepson is going to ride the..
..moon and go far away.
He is going abroad.
lstanbul. Look step-mother.
I've come from ldhar to lstanbul.
You run away too and come here.
Yes, but you'll be scared when
you see these huge buildings.
I'm not scared. Know why?
There's neither the school here,
neither father, nor his cane.
Guru. I'm so glad to see you.. come.
Come.
I wear a uniform. It's red.
And a cap too. I look good in it.
I work very hard.
I sell petrol cans.
Do you know what they say for
namaste here? Salaam Walekum.
Walekum Salaam
(Greetings in return).
You're amazing.
Hail divine Mother!
Why are you betting again?
You'll lose double of what you win.
Let it be, I'm telling you.
Come, this is not for us. Come.
You are amazing. Hail divine Mother!
One minute.
I'll open it..
Hail divine Mother! I've won!
You go.. or I go?
You shut his shop.
Guru, how did you know..
..the red ball was
under that very glass?
My eyes. Out of the three glasses,
one was smaller.
I just kept my eyes on that.
The spice business is conducted
here. Very big traders come here.
It's a business
that requires brains.
The sharper you are,
the luckier you are.
From tomorrow, there will be
a new trader amongst them..
Gurukanth Desai.
"You are the blue ocean.."
"I am the sand shore."
"Take me into your arms.."
"I've been yearning
from a long time."
"The shade of night and
the glimpse of moon.."
"If you want take a
glimpse at the moon."
"The shade of night and
the glimpse of moon.."
"If you want take a
glimpse at the moon."
"ln the boat of the moon,
come we have to go ashore.."
"You row slowly, the sea
shouldn't spill over.."
"O dear, collect
all the pink stars."
"O dear, collect all the
stars that are yearning."
"O dear, collect
all the pink stars."
"O dear, collect all the
stars that are yearning."
"When the blue sea awakens,
it takes you in the arms.."
"It sways and enchanted, it
kisses the face of the moonlight.."
"Your heart beats in my heart."
"I have sleepless
nights because of you."
"O dear, O dear."
"There is a pine in my heart."
"What does the smoke convey?"
"Smoke all around."
"The smoke always says."
"O dear, O dear."
GURU
How long have you worked here?
- How long you've worked here?
Seven years.
- Seven, sir.
Do you know how to wear a tie?
Where's your tie? Take it out.
This?
- Wear it.
I've heard complaints about you.
But I'm very
impressed with your work.
There have been some
complaints against you..
..but he's very
impressed with your work.
I'm promoting you to the
post of sales supervisor.
You can start work tomorrow.
Congratulations. - Say thank you.
Gurukanth, aren't you happy? He
has made you a sales supervisor.
Look, Robert sir has
signed it himself. See.
It took me thirteen years to
become a sales supervisor..
..just keep that tie on.
I don't want to wear a tie.
Nor do I want this promotion.
Why?
I want to return to my village.
When did this foolish idea
occur to you, may I ask?
After wearing this tie.
Why?
You like my work, so
does he, then why should..
..I work for that white man?
I'll work for myself.
You'll work for yourself?
Take it in writing. You can never
do anything for yourself. Write it.
Chagan sir, my
destiny is already written.
Let me take your leave.
I'll miss you.
You're taking all the fun with you.
Now we'll just slog here.
"No dear, no dear.."
"Clouds, please rain."
"The first shower of
rain is very sweet."
"Come on, go ahead."
"No dear.."
"Rain."
"Clouds, please rain."
"Wet mud."
"Come on, let's make..
..a house from the wet mud."
"Let's put swings on the green
branches of the mango tree."
"The clouds are thundering..
..and everyone has
taken the ploughs."
"The cattle with the
bells ringing all the way."
"I swam across."
"I went to the shore."
"No dear.."
Father, I'm leaving. You
don't like what I wish for.
The country's become free
so why not your daughter?
I've found my partner..
bless me so that I live happily.
Your loving daughter, Sujata.
"ln dark nights..
..it will rain heavily."
"The cloud will stop
me in every alley..
..will return after a thunder."
"My home..
..and the fountain of water."
"Don't forget or
everyone will question."
"I floated..
..and sang along."
"No dear.."
A bearded man has sent
this letter for you.
I don't have the courage
to run away and lead a life.
please forgive me, Sujata.
Yours, Bhanu patel.
Hey, come on. Hurry up.
Hey!
He is spread like a
python on the whole berth.
I have a reservation.
Reservation is only for the night.
Look out. lts still night.
I can sleep comfortably
till tomorrow morning.
It's morning. ln many places in
the world, its morning, do you know?
Can't think beyond the village.
Throw it when the train stops.
It won't fly back.
Oh God, I can't even cry in peace.
Good, you woke me.
My station's come.
If you cry early in the morning..
..you'll have to cry the whole day.
Sujata! Sujata!
Girl, alone? - Yes. Boarded
at the last station? - Yes.
This bogey, seat number thirty two.
She drenched the whole seat crying.
Come on.
- Thanks brother.
Sujata. You are here?
Does one leave like this
without telling anyone?
I searched you everywhere.
Come on.
Hey, step son, where
were you all these years.
I was saving myself from
your beatings, you lousy woman.
My brother has become an Englishman.
Come, Guru.
Sit. Sit.
Uncle, if he gives reason to
complain again, take care. Come.
Come Ramlal, look who has come.
Guru? I didn't recognize you.
How would you?
- You can't see after your marriage.
Has your wife come?
- Yes. - Guru, give him some money.
Give him twenty you fool.
Miser. Come.
Take it.
- Guru!
Look how big the school has grown.
Greetings sir.
Even on looking at the cane,
the hand begins to burn.
Must have received 10
or 20 lakhs canings.
And look at the
progress you've made!
If I'd known earlier,
I would have hit..
..you till you
became the prime Minister.
Father.
- For me?
Wonderful, dear!
How many days have you taken off?
As many as I want.
- What do you mean?
Meaning, I don't have to do job.
But, your brother
said that they've..
..promoted you and
tripled your salary.
Yes. - But I've worked
enough for the white man..
I want to set up my business.
My own business.
What do you know about business?
When I did business..
..I could hardly put
food on the table.
Everyone cannot do business.
- Father.
Just because you failed,
doesn't mean I won't pass.
Keep it. It'll help
you keep track of the..
..bad times that
will come in your life.
Ramlal, return his money.
- What? - Return his money.
If you setup your home,
with his money your..
..wife will run away.
You'll be ruined.
Go.. do business. Business.
No.. no,
- Go.
Guru what are you doing?
The principal will scream,
don't do that. No Guru..
Hey children, go
inside your classes.
Do you remember how we
would run up on this hill?
Remember, carrying huge tins,
fried snacks in one..
..snacks in the other!
Idiot, you've been selling something
or the other since childhood.
Move aside.
Three paisa profit
for one fried snack..
..and the fried
snacks weren't even hot.
After climbing all
these stairs we should..
..at least make
half a paisa profit..
Take fried snacks.
Snacks!
Father will never agree..
he is a money lender..
God of misers!
I have fifteen thousand. I
need another fifteen.. that's all.
He won't invest. He's saved
it for my sister's wedding.
Dowry?
- Yes.
How much?
Twenty five thousand.
I'll marry her.
What?
Marry her to me.
She is my elder sister. She
is elder to me by a year..
..so she's elder to
you by a year too.
So what if she's a year older? One,
two years is no big deal.
Don't talk without thinking.
Look, all I know is that..
..I'm ready to marry her.
Then we'll be business partners.
Fifty-fifty.
You will receive a dowry
and make me an equal partner?
You'll also be part of the dowry.
How do I tell father?
What will I say?
I won't be able to tell him.
Why are you scared? I'm marrying,
not stealing. I'll talk to him.
Have you come to talk about
marriage? Are you a broker?
Go back. We are not interested?
The last time I saw you.. you
were crying yourself hoarse.
I don't even know you. Why
would I cry in front of you?
You were crying in front of
the whole world in the train..
..reading some Bhanu
patel's letter. - Who are you?
Guru, who knows everything.
Didn't you sit on my legs?
My leg broke, it still hurts.
Then go to a doctor.
What have you come here for?
I am not here to take anything.
I've come to talk. About marriage.
Hold this.
Listen. Don't drag me into this.
Hey Tulsibhen. - Oh God.
- Where is uncle?
Uncle.
Do you recognize me?
No.
You shut down my
father's ghee shop..
..you even took away
all the buffaloes.
Master Kanthilal's son? - Yes. -
You're the boy who hit me on..
..my ear with a stick
and ran away, aren't you?
I was eight years old. Shall I sit?
You've come to make me
deaf from my other ear?
kanthilal.
- He has no business sense.
Now thanks to me, he
is the headmaster.
What are you? You
are in Turkey, right?
No, I'm here. I want to do
business here with your son Jignesh.
What business?
Many new things are
available there abroad.
I'll bring them and sell them here.
I'll make good profit.
And, what does your father say?
He says I'll be ruined.
Then you will definitely
make a profit. Don't worry.
But I've stopped
lending money these days.
I've to get my daughter married.
I'll marry your daughter and..
take good care of her.
I'll become a famous
man in five years.
My daughter is crazy.
Haven't you heard what those
idiot villagers are saying?
Jobless people keep
wagging their tongues.
There is no limit to their talks.
There was a sickly looking,
bearded boy like buffalo.
Used to just roam around with
a red flag and four laborers.
She wanted to marry him.
Have you heard this at least
or are you deaf too like me?
I was on the same train
in which she was fleeing.
I've seen a bit of the world.
I know right and wrong.
Just give me your blessing
and I'll take care of the girl.
What? - Just give me your blessing
I'll take your leave.
Mother.
"Live your life in love."
What is this? Why
are you leaving with..
..your
brother-in-law after marriage?
You are crazy. Where is your wife?
Don't scream. She's not coming.
Why not?
- Let it be.
What catastrophe
is keeping her here?
Don't know. perhaps she doesn't
like it. Maybe she doesn't like me.
How can she not like you?
The lousy woman is mad.
Not all women are
sweet like my stepmother..
Come on, bless me.
Bless me.
- Live long.
I shall take your leave.
Hey lizard! Elder brother.
Take care.
I know.. this isn't your wish.
But still, your blessings..
May God give you sense..
What else can I say?
It's time for your train to leave.
Don't.. don't go.
What?
What if I die here all alone?
But, you said you
didn't want to come with me.
You could have asked me again.
Look, you're not asking me even now.
But you don't even have any luggage?
Can't you buy me four saris?
Guru, come.
And ticket?
Do I need a ticket
to sit on your lap?
Come. Come running.
Bye. I'll write a letter.
- Come.. come.
"Love is wonderful.."
"The ground has
disappeared from below the feet.."
"Love is wonderful.."
"The ground has
disappeared from below the feet.."
Where is the yarn market?
- That way.
Where does all the buying and
selling happen? - Upstairs sir.
Why do they shout so much?
How will we do business here?
Jignesh. If you don't shout.
You'll be left behind.
And when we shout,
everyone else will shut up.
1550! 1550.
Sir, Mathura Das?
1350 given. Given.
- Listen.
Are you Mathura Das?
- Could be. Why?
I want to do yarn business.
I've come from ldhar village.
I want to do yarn
business with my own money.
But wherever I go people
say that there's a union.
Yes there is.
Without its permission you
can't do business over here.
You must become a member.
1550. 1550.
Your bid's too high. If
you go to Salem market..
..you'll get it much cheaper.
Quiet. Don't teach me business. If
you want to trade become a member.
So make me a member.
There's a five year waiting period.
It won't happen. Go on.
Don't waste my time.
But you're not
letting me do business..
..nor are you making me a member.
It's not in my hands.
Don't irritate me.
Arzaan Contractor is the
president of the association.
Azraan.. who?
- Arzaan Contractor.
You can become a
member only with his letter.
You won't become a member.
Are you a fortune teller?
I am doing business
here since 20 years.
Twenty five thousand
like you come here everyday.
A villager won't do here. Go away.
1300. 1350. Yes given.
- Mr. Das. Mr. Das.
Yes. - I'll stand right
next to you and do business.
And I'll wipe out twenty five
thousand like you. Just watch.
Come.
What price did you quote?
Good shot, sir.
What do you want?
Your letter. I want to
trade in the cloth market..
..but they say
unless I get your letter..
..I can't become a member there.
Come to the office.
I have, sir. For four weeks.
I know Bhola's entire
family history.. your watchman.
Do you play golf?
I play, but not this.
Take it, play.
This ball should go there. If
it does, you'll get the letter.
I should put this ball
in that hole? - Yes.
And you will give me the letter?
- Of course.
For sure right, if I do it?
Try it.
Look at my good shot, sir.
What's your name?
- Gurukanth Desai.
You'll give me the letter?
Ok. I'll see.
I've collected money for
business with great difficulty.
I'll take care.
ln my village, help
is never forgotten.
It'll happen. If
you don't mind. Yes?
Thank you, sir. You'll see,
business will benefit with me.
Two paisa.
- No.
Two paisa is too
much for that. Here.
Let me get the change!
Where's the fire?
I've got something for you.
For me?
- Yes.
What?
- I'll show you.
What have you bought for me?
- Come.
Have you bought this for me?
Yes, don't you like it?
I thought you'll get
me lots of saris..
..jewelry, diamonds, 8-10 big cars.
I have brought it all.
I'll show you.
You can see it now.
Could you see it?
No, but the whole world will see us.
I can see it.. a
big house.. a palace.
I can see the lintel.. burnt
on the gas. No food tonight.
I see a factory.. very big.
Even bigger than Burma Shell.
I see clothes in the wash.. wet..
..you'll have to go in
your underwear tomorrow.
I can see you, fat, with a
Rs.900,000 necklace, fat bangles..
..walking with a swagger..
all of five hundred pounds.
I'll never be fat.
Ok slim one! Wearing
Rs.900,000 necklace..
..fat bangles..
walking with a swagger.
Very happy.
Very, very, very, happy.
With you.
Guru.
- The brother-in-law is here.
It's over. It's all over.
What?
- Our business is over. - What?
But what happened?
That Contractor's
rejected our application.
Can't be. He gave me his word.
Am I lying to you? I'm
coming from his office.
He tore up our
application after reading it.
So do we go back to
the village now?
If we don't, we'll
be out on the streets.
I say, let's pack our bags
and go to the village.
What is there for dinner sister?
Who are you?
I live here.
I don't live here, okay?
Then why are you
staring at my building?
Why? Do I need a
letter even to look now?
The building is on the road,
the road is the Government's..
..these eyes are mine..
the country is free.
I can stare at whoever,
whenever I want.
Don't bug me early in the morning.
Go watch your dog piss.
Very good.. anger early in the
morning is very good. Let's walk.
What's your name?
Manik Das Gupta.. - You've
turned your city into a club.
This one can't come here.
That one can't come here.
You just wear a suit
and talk in English.
They've turned
Bombay into a dog. Dog!
Good. Being angry with
Bombay is very good.
Not on Bombay. I am angry with
one man.. I want to slap him.
The president of our
traders association..
Arzaan Contractor. He
promised me four months ago..
..that he'll give me a
letter of membership.
Then he tore up my
application and threw it away.
He doesn't wake up before ten
o'clock, how will you slap him?
Do you know him?
Since he was this little.
Can you do something for me?
I don't believe in giving
or taking recommendations.
But you look like a big
social communist leader.
You should help the poor.
Against this rich Contractor.
And if I say no?
That's a problem.
I can't hear the word 'no.'
I like it. I like it very much.
Come to my office.
Will you get the letter for me?
I'll make sure your voice is heard.
How? - I own a
newspaper Swatantra Samachar.
If you're speaking the truth then..
I will fight your war.
But if you've lied, I'll slap you.
I've just arrived in Bombay;
I haven't learnt to lie yet.
Good, come tomorrow.
Trading big shot Arzaan Contractor..
..the country is free but..
..when will the trade
markets be free from..
..their president,
Arzaan Contractor?
Mr. Contractor considers himself
the undisputed lord of the union..
..and Mr. Gurukanth
Desai as his enemy.
Now nobody can stop Guru
from becoming a businessman.
A very big businessman.
Bigger than anybody..
am I talking too big?
A bit.
Mathura Das.
Here I am, right beside you.
You have come. But you won't last.
There are a dime a dozen like you..
Those whom you have seen,
only you know about them.
I only know that there's just
one person like me here. Only Guru.
Greetings.
- Greetings.
- Greetings. Move. - Move.
Greetings.
- Greetings.
I didn't know you had so
many complaints against me.
You should have spoken to me.
Not in the papers, like this.
How do we tell you sir?
It's difficult to meet you.
Today you're in
trouble so you've come here..
..or you are found only at the club.
It seems like this
Union doesn't require me.
And I don't like
staying where I'm not needed.
That is why I am resigning
from presidency. I am resigning.
No. - Let him go,
someone else will come along.
Quiet. You needn't
go contractor sir.
He has decided, Mr. Das.
Now even God can't make him
change his decision, isn't it?
My decision won't change.
But, times will.
Anything could
happen tomorrow itself.
And if it does,
don't come crying to me.
If we're going to be that scared,
how'll we do business?
Don't worry.. we are the fearless.
What was your name?
Not was, it still is.. and
will always be. Gurukanth Desai.
Where is that villager, Guru?
Where?
Oh uncle.
- Okay, okay.
What is it?
You opened a new office
and didn't even call me?
Meenu, what do we do with him..
..wring his neck or
break his teeth? - Both.
Shall I do it?
Which tooth shall I break?
This one. Come on mare.
My name is Meenakshi.
Jalkukdi. - Meenu. - Jalkukdi.
- No. - Yes. - No.
She won't accept defeat.
Uncle, it's too
small a place for you..
He's lying. He was
afraid you would scold him.
That he doesn't have faith in
himself and has to depend on God.
He was right.
No. God and I don't get along.
If you offer it as a
sweet I'll eat it.
You'll get both or neither.
She's smarter than you.
Why don't you treat the
offering as a sweet and..
..I'll treat the
vermilion as just a colour.
You will have your way.
Such a struggle for a tiny sweet!
- Hail divine Mother.
Who is this villager?
My brother-in-law and partner.
What will you do?
Cotton.
- Suit business.
Very good.. a fight
on the very first day.
My brother is sleeping outside.
I am not asking you to wake him.
What will you do now?
What do you think?
You beast. What work will
you do to earn a living?
You brought us here
like a big leader..
..how are you going
to clothe and feed us?
polyester.
What's that?
Clothe.. Shiny..
..naughty just like you.
You beast.. I made a
big mistake marrying you.
I can't understand whether you..
..love your yarn more or me.
Should I tell you?
Das was saying polyester
business is dangerous. - Let him.
Are you brainless? The whole
world is into cotton and you..
When you see the profit..
..you'll say wow Guru,
how intelligent you are!
How much did you invest?
All the money.
Oh God, you'll kill us.
You've shut it down.
We will be ruined.
You'll know when we are really dead.
Why did you shut it down?
-This won't do.
What's the matter?
- This won't do.
What happened? - They've
shut down the market. - Why?
They say it's gambling.
Gambling?
- Yes.
But the fun of business is
predicting which price will rise..
..and fall, where the
losses and profits are..
..that shows the
acumen of the businessman.
You think that. The
Government calls that gambling.
Gambling.
Then tell the Government to
stop lotteries. That is gambling.
The race at Mahalakshmi,
astrology. All that's gambling too.
You came and destroyed our business.
Not me.
Your friend Contractor has
done it. And that too with bribes.
No problem.
We'll start our market here.
Yes.
- Wait! Wait!
Guru, what are you doing?
You'll go to jail and..
..send everybody else in as well.
See this.
- What is this?
A Government notice
from an I.A.S. officer..
Do you know the meaning of this?
It's the law now. Law!
Mr. Das, if a law
can be made in a day..
..then it can also be
changed in a day too.
Nothing will be changed.
k.R. Menon..
..the I.A.S. officer is very strict.
He doesn't listen to anybody.
Everything is ruined.
Who are you? Who are you?
- Come in. come in.
Come. Keep the goods there.
Come.. this way.
Who is that? Come.
Greetings sir.
- Hey wait!
Are you Mr. k.R. Menon sir?
Who are you? -That cloth trading..
..it stopped because
of your men right?
What is this? - That notice
has your signature, right. Come.
Come. Come.
Unni, ask him to stop.
- Come in.
Come.. come.. come..
There.
- Stop it.
All the goods are yours.
What nonsense? Who are you?
My father-in-law is a businessman,
moneylender.
In my village, if people
who borrow money from him..
..don't pay back, he
mortgages everything.
If clarified butter shop is..
..shut down then
people give him buffaloes.
I had a polyester
shop that you shut down.
Now all this is yours.
It's top quality polyester, sir.
Make clothes for the children.
Wear suits. You'll
look good. Greetings.
Come on everybody. Come on.
Gurukanth Desai.
Just see who it is.
- Gurukanth Desai!
Menon sir, you? Greetings.
I've been looking
for you for four days.
You should have at least
given your name, address.
Jignesh. Yes? - Come. Mr.
Menon, A very big I.A.S. officer.
Look, my record is impeccable.
If the higher
authorities find out about the..
..polyester, I will lose my job.
What can I do about that sir?
Take it all back,
neighbours have begun to ask.
Sir, I can understand.
But until the..
..market opens I can't
take the goods back.
Are you threatening me?
No sir, but the other traders were..
..also going to come to your
house to leave their goods.
What nonsense is this?
What can I do?
How can I re-open the market?
I'm an illiterate villager,
I don't know much.
But if you locked the market doors..
..then you must have the keys too.
And if I say no?
What?
And if I say 'no'?
I don't understand the word 'no'.
And one more thing,
the traders are asking..
..for your residence address
everyday. Should I give it?
Glory to Guru!
You are great.
- Wonderful.
Brother Guru,
you've done a great job.
Guru has come. He has
brought gifts for all.
What?
- He's given one to Mr. Sharma.
What have you brought for me?
You forgot the lame Jalkukdi?
Close your eyes.
Don't open them. Don't open them.
Now open them.
A wedding sari!
- Of course.
You'll marry me?
For seven lifetimes..
Grandpa.
- Very nice.
I'll show it to everyone.
Go.
- So Brother Guru?
Why are you calling me brother Guru?
I'm like your son.
Everyone addresses
you with this name.
The name suits you.
Grandpa. Come on, get up.
Leave that. Come on, get up.
I know you're not even..
..going to touch this..
..you look like
Gandhi in this loin cloth.
But when you travel abroad..
..and it's very cold you can
make a coat like Nehru and wear it.
It'll look very nice.
You are bribing me with
Gandhi and Nehru's names.
No. I don't know how
to shake hands and..
..say thank you in English.
That's why.
If you don't like it..
..then break both my neck
and teeth. Come on, bless me.
This mischief is
what I like about you..
..suddenly you speak with
honesty and intelligence.
Don't ever let go of this habit.
Grandpa.
Whatever happens, I'll
never let go of you.
I promise.
"You have to come."
- Want more? - No, thanks.
please, I don't want.
Gulp it down in one shot.
Come on, bottoms up!
- No. No.
He won't drink, his
wife will scream at him.
All wives scold..
..if you drink a bit,
you'll hear less of it.
I apologize for being late.
Cut it, dear.
The work was such. I was
doing our trial balance..
..our profits are up
by 300% in six months.
And the price of polyester
has gone through the roof!
Very good.
But don't relax,
because if the Shakti..
..family has worked
for 18 hours till today..
..we will now work 25
hours per day. - 25 hours!
Ask why?
- Why?
Because, the Shakti
family will not only trade..
..we will manufacture
kela silk (polyester).
We are opening a factory.
Very good.
Foreign machines will produce the..
..English named
kela silk.. polyester.
polyester.
Just because you've
bought a car doesn't mean..
..that you dream of
opening a factory.
Shut up! Unless you dream
you'll be stuck to Idhai.. drink..
But.. - We've also seen the land.
25 acres right next to your village.
Walk carefully.. don't
be in such a hurry..
Who wants to walk? I want to run..
I'm carrying you in my arms,
don't move, you'll fall.
And the money?
Are you Contractor? Will
the banks give you a loan?
To hell with Contractor and banks..
..we will go to the public and
start a factory. Give ten rupees..
..and become the owner..
public issue.
If the factory earns,
so will everyone.
permission for the public
issue will come in one month.
Fantastic! Let's have
another one on this!
Have it! Come on, have it!
- Guru.
You didn't ask me even once.
You could've at
least taken my opinion.
My dear dowry sweet.
You wouldn't have..
..let us sell polyester,
or anything else.
You were about to pack up
and go back to the village.
We are partners in business..
..it's not just yours.
You just stay behind me..
and watch the world.
Don't poke your nose in between.
If you stick your nose in,
I'll turn you into polyester..
..and sell you to a foreign lady.
Jignesh.
Little prince is upset.. no problem.
I'll pacify him and bring him back..
..but empty the bottle. Understood?
Yes, we will empty it.
Hey, wait.
Where are you going?
Come back. Everyone's watching.
I can't get along with him.
This is not a silly game
that you get upset and leave.
Come back. Should I
fall at your feet? Come.
I'm going to the village.
We'll all go together and put up a
huge board. Shakti factory. Come.
I don't want to do
anything with him.
people will say that
you're jealous of him.
Who will say?
- Even I will..
You've gone mad and blind.
Hey brother Jignesh. Your
problem is with me. Fight with me.
Speak properly to your sister. Okay?
You're senseless. You've forgotten..
..that he's looked after both of
us. Learn to understand a person.
He only understands money. Do
you know why he married you?
He was a true friend. He
married a girl who was eloping.
He would have married you
even if you were handicapped.
You know why? Tell her..
Why are you talking like a child?
He married you for dowry.
Tell him not to lie.
Ask him.
Guru bhai.
Father had promised a
big dowry, 25 thousand.
That's why he got married. He
wanted to start his business.
Tell him not to lie..
Sister, you're just
capital for him.
He's lying.
Is this true?
"Don't go as everyone
look like stranger to me.."
"I feel lonely.."
"I don't feel good without you."
"I don't feel good."
"O dear, what is life without you.."
"Without you, the nights
are tasteless, O beloved.."
"The nights are dry and
there is solitude all around."
"Without you, the nights
are tasteless, O beloved.."
"O dear, what is life without you.."
"Don't go away."
"Don't go leaving me alone."
"Don't go..
..as there will be no
fun in the rainy season."
"Without you, the nights
are tasteless, O beloved.."
"Now I cannot
spend it without you.."
"Without you, the nights
are tasteless, O beloved.."
"O dear, what is life without you.."
"Without you."
"Without you the moonlit is dim."
"The sunshine looks farce."
"Without you the gold looks copper."
"Life is precious with you."
"Come, as I am
having sleepless nights."
"O dear, what is life without you.."
"Without you, the nights
are tasteless, O beloved.."
"The nights are dry and
there is solitude all around."
"O dear, what is life without you.."
Fight with the whole world,
but not with me.
If you're with me, I
can win the whole world.
Then why are you
hanging on to me? Come on..
Where?
To beat the world!
Hey elder brother,
you also touch it.
Hey Mr. Ghanshyam.
When did you come?
I've come on time, haven't I?
Brother Guru! Brother Guru!
- Yes.
How was the Europe and America tour?
It was a very successful one.
There was only one difficulty.
I didn't get to eat food
cooked by her. I starved.
You're being called the
business king of lndia.
Do you have Shakti shares?
- Yes.
Then you are lndia's
business king too.
Guru brother. people
are pointing fingers..
..at your growth.
You're growing too fast.
This is a race. And I run
to win, not for pleasure.
Look, Meenu.
Whatever you own is mine.
Now tell me, will you marry me?
No.
- Hey Jalkukdi. - Gurukanth.
You are so nicely decked up.
Just like a bride.
Really? Actually I knew.
That's why this parsi uncle's
been troubling me since long.
I told him move on,
my husband's coming.
So when are you marrying me?
Leave elder sister. Let's
get into my car and run away.
Can you cook like her?
Hello, Mr. Guru.
I'm talking about love and
you're talking about your stomach.
How do you live with him?
With great difficulty. - Greetings
brother Guru. - Where's grandpa?
America. He'll be back in two weeks.
Brother Guru!
Greetings sister-in-law.
Contractor sir. -Greetings.
Meenu.
- Hello.
Brother Guru,
someone has been waiting..
..since long to meet you. Come.
Sister. Are you expecting?
How did you know? I
haven't even told him as yet.
Your face is glowing. And it
will be a girl, just like me.
Dad. Gurukanth Desai.
So you're brother Guru.
And you're the senior Mr.
Contractor. It's a pleasure.
The pleasure is entirely mine.
I've a present for you.
That's why I wanted you
to come to the wedding.
But I brought a present only
for your daughter. Not for you.
A blank cheque. Your
mathematics is excellent.
So fill it up. With any
number that you like. Fill it up.
Everything has a price,
brother Guru.
Where you've reached today,
is amazing.
You've made your own way.
It's wonderful.
But the way ends here.
Don't put it down. If
you keep it down today..
..you might not get another
opportunity tomorrow, to pick it up.
Lousy old man.
He wants to buy me.
He says everything has a price.
Will he put a price tag on me too?
150 years. What he made in
150 years, I made in 10 years.
Is there any match? No.
What's going on?
Cashier. Get hold
of all our friends..
..from the press.
All of them. Right now.
Call them, go to their homes,
wake them up, do what you have to.
From tomorrow, every
newspaper in the..
..country should carry
an expose on Contractor.
Tell them. That Contractor's suits..
..and cars shine but
his machines are useless.
Old, rusted, very cheap.
Cashier.
Contractor's name should
become a curse. A curse.
"Brother Guru,
brother Guru has come.."
"He will cause a stir.."
"Brother Guru,
brother Guru has come.."
"He will cause a stir.."
"Brother Guru,
brother Guru has come.."
"He will cause a stir.."
"Brother Guru,
brother Guru has come.."
"He will cause a stir.."
"Brother Guru,
brother Guru has come.."
"He will cause a stir.."
"Brother Guru,
brother Guru has come.."
"He will cause a stir.."
"Brother Guru,
brother Guru has come.."
This is the Swatantra Samachar..
The lndependent.
This very newspaper has
destroyed the British.
It didn't get scared of anybody.
It has fought for ideals and
principles. But it never got sold.
I was away for a month and you all
sold it. You stabbed me in the back.
ln a month you've dressed the
newspaper in Guru's safari suits.
Hey.
- Yes.
Who gave you this?
Guru?
- Yes. - Take it off.
I said take it off!
That too.
Now pick up both of them and
throw them in the dustbin.
Editor sir.
- Yes? - I hear you've a new car.
Don't you have shame? Don't
you have even a little shame?
We have to apologize to the country.
Tomorrow morning's edition
will have an apology letter.
The page has already been composed.
- Then stop it! Stop it!
You've made false allegations.
You have supported the wrong man.
So you have to apologize.
Go. Go! Send for Shyam Saxena.
Shyam. - Have you
gone deaf? Shyam Saxena.
Send him and tell Guru to come too.
- Yes sir.
Grandpa.
These sweets have come
especially for you from Junaghar.
What's wrong? You look troubled.
Can I do something?
You can do anything, Isn't it?
- Yes.
Nothing is difficult for you.
You just keep throwing
your money everywhere.
Grandpa, there are all
kinds of people in the world.
And everyone has a price. What
say brother? Here. Sweetmeat.
That's why I carry two
kinds of slippers with me.
One made of silver and one of gold.
I hit them with whichever of
the two they want and move ahead.
And which slipper
do you have for me?
For you, it's Khadi (cotton cloth).
So you will hit me
with a slipper too.
Shyam. What do you
think of brother Guru?
What can I say?
Feel free and say it.
Brother Guru is the biggest
hope of the lndian industry.
A champion businessman.
I am not asking you
for an advertisement.
Speak honestly.
To speak honestly, he is a disease
who should be locked up in jail..
..and the keys
thrown away in the drain.
Hey Jalkukdi. Who is this great
man who is praising me so much?
And why do you feel this way?
His growth rate is 400%.
Unbelievable.
But he is increasing
corruption and greed..
..at double the rate
that he is growing..
..with his gold and silver slippers.
Have you called me to beat
me with a stick Grandpa?
I've not even started yet.
Shyam.
If you and I break the
law we would be scared.
But he is proud of breaking the law.
And he doesn't just
break or bend the law.
He buries it and then
builds a beautiful park on it..
..the one with
flowers and fountains.
And after some time people
forget that this place is stolen.
I think his factory at Veraval..
- Grandpa..
If you want to tell me something
why don't you just tell me straight?
Shyam, can you strip him
before the whole world?
The whole world wears my clothes.
You'll have to strip everyone.
Can you stop this man or not?
No.
Neither him, nor this newspaper,
nor you, nor your khadi army.
I'll stop him. I'll stop him.
Brother Shyam..
This cloth and weight are a
result of a lot of hard work.
You also work hard to fight with me.
If you want to fight Gurukanth,
become Gurukanth.
But there is only one Gurukanth.
"Guru brother,
Guru brother has come.."
"He will cause a stir.."
Guru brother,
Guru brother has come.."
"He will cause a stir.."
"Guru brother, Guru brother."
You look very beautiful.
It is so easy to say that. When you
give birth to a child, you'll know.
Walk around with a huge
tummy like a bedding roll.
Vomit from morning to night.
And on top of that, get kicked!
A child is small but it is so..
What do you want? That my
tummy too should become like this?
I look at least 3-4 months pregnant.
Boy or girl?
It's not just one.
Then? Twins?
There are 25000 people inside.
What are they saying?
Guru Brother .
Guru Brother. Mike.
Welcome Shakti family!
Enjoy.
It is for the first time
in India that a company's..
..meeting is being held like this.
You know why? The Shakti
family is so big that..
..it can't fit into any small place.
Welcome all of you.
My special apologies to our
brothers from Gujarat..
..who've skipped
their afternoon siesta.
Do you know, a few years ago
Shakti family was in debt.
From the bank, government.
Then I came to you with my
arms spread. What did you do?
You emptied your vaults.
The result? Today, we are free.
We are doing
business with our own money.
Our own investment. Our own profit.
When I first came to Bombay..
it's been many years..
..I had come with just
two shirts and a coat.
But today the whole of lndia..
..wears our clothes!
Clap.
But I know you aren't happy.
- We're happy, brother Guru.
No. No. You are not happy at all.
Why?
You'll be happy only when
we open four more factories.
So Shakti family, what do you say?
Shall we open four more factories?
Do you want to become
lndia's biggest company?
I've grown old. Can't hear you.
Say it even louder. - Yes!
How many Shakti shares do you have?
I'm a reporter.
He's a magician.
Write good things about him.
poverty will disappear if we
have ten men like brother Guru.
I will definitely write.
Make sure to read..
..next Saturday's
Swatantra Samachar.
Fine.
"Come on gamble. 1 , 2, 3, 4.."
Balu. That lighthouse
shouldn't come in the frame. - Yes.
This shouldn't look like lndia.
And make sure the print looks old.
They shouldn't look like
today's pictures. -Yes sir.
You want to click fake
photos and pass them as truth?
If it's a lie, then let ..
.. your brother Guru come
forward and say it's a lie.
Just move aside.
Tear it. The powder should be seen.
You come this side.
And all of you come out.
Balu, ready?
- Ready.
You've made up the entire story.
It's written by brother Guru. I'm
just presenting it. Balu click them.
"Come on gamble, let
it go as it goes.."
"Let's see what happens."
They dumped cartons like this?
Yes. And all empty ones. There
was lime powder in some of them.
Sent to fake companies
with fake addresses.
Meaning, he sent
empty cartons abroad..
..and showed full cartons as export.
And doing this he also got the..
..polyester import license.
700% profit.
You have to hand it to brother Guru.
He found a way to
profits even from empty boxes!
But the way was of lies.
All fraud and cheating.
But even you're lying.
This is the truth. Shakti's truth.
Naked truth.
These are all lies! Fake!
They must have shot it
somewhere here in Bombay..
..and are passing it off as Arabia.
- Yes.
First of all, I'll stop
advertising in Grandpa's paper.
Why should they earn from us?
No.
lncrease them in
Swatantra Samachar(newspaper).
If we were giving
them 10 advertisements..
..in a month, make it 30.
But brother Guru..
Balance sheets, profits, new
companies. publish all of them.
I wish that when Grandpa
wakes up every morning..
..he should know about our progress.
Brother Guru..
- What happened doctor?
The same thing that happens
usually with your company.
Double profit.
Congratulations, they are twins!
Cashier sir. Send a
telegram to my father.
Tell him Guru is coming.
- Yes.
My God Suju! There
really are two of them.
Name.
Disha.
- I only thought of one.
Drishti. Even I had thought of one.
A bonus. Buy one-get one free.
It's a pair!
Buy one, get one free.
Is it so?
By one, get one free.
"It is a pair.."
"Not one but two.."
"Tell me Guru.."
"Tell me what will happen.."
"If there were two pairs of one.."
"If there were two pairs of wives.."
"Tell me Guru.."
"Tell me what would have happened.."
"The chains of the feet
would also be not one, but two.."
"The handcuffs also would
also be not one, but two.."
"Night and day, I
would have chanted.."
"Tulsi behan, not one, but two."
"It is a pair.."
"Not one but two.."
"Tell me Guru.."
"Tell me what will happen.."
"Brother Babu, greetings.
Brother Raju greetings.."
"Sister Kanta,
greetings. What is your name.."
"The round moon, if
there were two moons.."
"There would be one for the
day and one for the night.."
"During load-shedding, the
moon would have been lighted up.."
"The people would have said,
how did this happen.."
"I got a kick, the cannabis gave
me a high, that's how it happened.."
"If one and one make a pair."
"Then there would be
two wives at home."
"Tell me Guru.."
"pair."
"Dear."
"Not one, not one but two.."
"We will lift the palanquin.."
"Come on a mare."
"You have gone crazy.."
"Your face is broken.."
"Your imitation is fake.."
"Not one, not one but two.."
"You have gone crazy.."
"Your face is broken.."
"Your imitation is fake.."
"Not one.."
"Leave cannabis and break your leg..
..come and sit at home."
"Not one.."
"Little droplets make ocean."
"I am getting high on the cannabis."
"My doll."
"Guru's doll."
"Stay awake at night."
"Tulsi behan, Not one, but two."
Shakti's fake strength.
Brother Guru plays a
new game of corruption.
Shakti's new shares are
selling at high prices..
..but the shares are being
bought by brother Guru's men.
You are bent on crucifying him.
Don't you think the more
you write the bigger..
..the hero he will become?
- Really.
Even I've applied
for his new shares.
You?
I've to think of my future.
Who else will? You?
What happened?
What happened? - I don't know sir.
- What do you mean you don't know?
Go check the power room.
- Yes sir.
Shankar, come here.
- Murpani! Any news?
Who could be behind this? 3 guesses.
Gurukanth.. Gurukanth.. Gurukanth.
The power failure is..
- Only in our press.
What do you mean?
- The power is off only here? - Yes.
You go yourself and ensure printing
resumes in 15 minutes. - Yes sir.
I think we won't have
power till late at night.
I don't care. You?
I don't either.
You know what I want to do?
You want to have tea. With ginger.
I want to sing.
So sing. It's your
grandfather's press.
I want to dance.
Fast, fast then slow
then fast, then slow..
I want to live for
three days, without pain.
Without multiple sclerosis..
..medicines,
wheelchair. Just three days.
"The morning light.."
Why are you looking
at me like that?
"Of the speechless morning,
it hums.."
"It is the noise of the light.."
You were going to
come to bless them.
I had to come to you.
Good. It's good that they are girls.
They'll be like just like you.
Make them brave, independent.
Get them used to
living without the father.
perhaps I have to send
your father to jail.
How long are you going to fight?
Till I win.
Don't you love him at all?
Don't you think of him as your son?
I asked him the same question..
..and got the same answer.
Silence.
What is this fight about? Why
are both of you behaving like this?
Where's your husband?
- Office.
Are you calling him up?
He doesn't know I'm here.
Don't do that grandpa.
Guru Brother.
Manik Das Gupta here.
Don't send your wife to beg.
Tell Motwani to check the proof.
- Yes.
Are you all right,
sir? Are you all right?
Why are you hitting the car?
Hit me! Why are you running away?
I know who sent you!
Tell him I'm not scared!
Guru...you?
Did you send them? - Whom?
- You send them, didn't you?
What are you talking about?
You know what I'm talking about.
They're after your blood.
So?
Just wanted to scare him.
Done with just Rs.15000.
I don't know what I would've done..
..if it were anyone
else who had done this.
He is like a father to me..
..and one never hits their father.
Meaning if someone
hurls a stone at us..
..we don't do anything.
We remain quiet?
Don't stay quiet.
Move ahead. If they write,
let them write..
..if they publish, let them,
if they hurl stones, let them.
If they talk about yesterday, let
them. We will talk about tomorrow.
We've come this far
together with our hard work.
Four sheets of paper can't
bring Shakti Corporation down.
Listen, tighten your belt.
Because until..
..we build a bigger
petro-chemical company..
..than Burma Shell, we
won't rest. Understood?
Why doesn't it rain the whole year?
Why isn't there cold in Bombay?
Why doesn't it snow?
Will you marry me?
It would be such fun if the
whole sea gets filled with snow.
Didn't you hear or you
don't want to marry me?
I want you to drown
in the sea and die.
Then how will I marry?
Do you know what this is?
- Multiple Sclerosis.
And do you know what that is?
A disease of the central
nervous system that has no cure.
It is one thing to read about
it and another to live with it.
I wake up in the morning.
Apart from waking..
..up in the morning,
I can't do anything.
I've had an attack every
other month since I was ten.
Nothing remains beautiful,
everything seems empty.
If Hamsa is careless,
then the bed gets wet..
Can you sleep on a rubber sheet?
"The sweet smell of the night.."
When do we marry?
"I love silences.." - You're
making fun of me, aren't you?
Your grandpa had
said the same thing.
I tried explaining but
he wouldn't understand.
I'll go very far
away in four hundred..
..and nineteen days..
- And then?
"Brightness.."
Then I want every
single one of those..
..four hundred and nineteen days.
"Of the speechless morning,
it hums.."
Marry me.
"I love the light.."
No.
please marry me, Meenu.
- No.
Meenu.
"The thrilling moments.."
"The clouds of love.."
"The clouds playing with snow.."
After six months! The new minister's
given us ten minutes! Ten minutes.
If his uncle was there, I
would've got a meeting like this.
Ten minutes is enough
for you, brother Guru.
No Cashier. You can only
say no in ten minutes.
I've had it with hearing a no.
Don't feel bad, brother Guru.
Just do some magic on this minister.
Or we'll all be in trouble.
How?
Brother Guru.
Careful. He's an honest man.
Greetings sir.
- You're in the papers everyday.
Your uncle was a very
good friend of mine.
It isn't necessary that
his friends are mine too.
A lot is being written against you.
There's a saying in my village.
When people speak against you..
..then you must be progressing.
I'm interested in the
progress of the nation.
Not yours.
You are running such a big
ministry at such a young age..
Look, I know people like you very
well and want to stay away from you.
I saw your petrochemical project
files. It's full of irregularities.
No. I haven't come to
talk about the factory..
I've come for your advice.
Actually I've this burden
on me. A very big burden.
Your uncle left something with me.
As a deposit. I'm an
ordinary man sir, I don't know much.
You just tell me what to do with it.
Should I return it to you..
..or have it sent overseas,
what do I do? It's very heavy sir.
Anyone would collapse
under it.. me, you.. anybody..
What happened? What happened?
Can this helicopter land anywhere?
- Yes.
Captain! Land at a good sweet shop.
The minister himself will come for..
..the inaugural function.
- Wow! Brother Guru.
Sandeep Mukherjee, Hindustan Times.
Oh Mr. Mukherjee, come, come.
I was waiting for you.
I am very pleased.
When you called up, I was surprised.
I was surprised to
hear that a newspaper..
..wanted to write
something nice about us.
It's quite a big factory.
Big? It took seventeen
months and five days to build.
So fast? - Our brother Guru
does everything in a flash.
How long have you
known brother Guru?
From Turkey. Yes.
We delivered petrol cans.
And today, I'm the
director of this entire factory.
Where are these machines from?
From Dupoint.
Do you know where Dupoint is?
In U.S.A.
No, it's in America.
- Click it. - Yes.
What's your output?
55,000 tonnes.
55,000 tonnes! Sure?
Sure?
- I'm a director of the company.
But Ghanshyam sir, I had heard
that you've government permission..
..to produce only 23,000 tonnes.
Take this.
- It is not written anywhere that..
..we can't produce
more than that right?
Understand.
Government language is such.
Click it.
- But you have shown machinery..
..with the capacity
of only 23,000 tonnes.
So how come the output is double?
We are hard working people.
We used the spare
parts lying around.
Come on, click. - Which means you
have permission for six spinning..
..lines but have set up
twelve spinning lines.
One minute. Who are you?
Great Ghanshyam sir!
You smuggled in six..
..spinning lines as spare parts
and brought them to the country..
..without paying import duty.
And you set up the whole factory.
You are masters of conning.
I asked you who are you?
I am a reporter, but
you are a smuggler.
Dog! You breed of a dog!
Easy. If this photo's printed..
..just think who will
become the street dog..
Get out! Get out! I said get out!
ln the place of one factory,
you are running two.
Without permission,
without import duty..
..and without sanction.
You are cheating the
excise and export departments.
And you are boasting of
running a big company?
Tell me, what should I write?
Get out of here!
Get out of here
before I lose control!
Thank you Ghanshyam Das sir.
- Get out or..
Don't miss the papers tomorrow.
With photo!
One man is working here..
..and all you are attacking him.
One day uncle said that nobody..
..could swim to the other side.
Then, what did he say?
Take a bet!
- Take a bet!
And what was the bet?
- Jhumpa's dance!
And papa jumped in the water.
And how was the water? - Cold.
Very cold.
So papa kept swimming..
and what did he see?
A very big fish.
- A very big fish.
Which fish was it?
- Shark.
Listen. phone call for you.
We're escaping from
the shark.. one minute..
It's Rinku, Das' daughter, from village.
Yes, Rinku dear.. tell me.
Brother Guru. Slit his
wrists with a vegetable knife.
He was in the back room.
No one knew for half an hour..
Enough..
Go out. You all sit outside.
I've come to slap you.
Slap you so hard that this pain..
..will feel like nothing.
Wants to die!
Do one thing. Kill me.
Here, slit my wrists too.
Because after you, it'll be my turn.
We've been together since Turkey.
Would you go leaving me alone..
just like that?
If anything happens to
you because of my mistake..
..I can't bear it Guru.
Look. Look.. look at me.
I'm happy now.
When that headmaster went..
I didn't shed a tear..
..step mother died, I didn't cry..
..it's just that you're so ugly..
..looking at such an ugly face..
that it's making me cry..
Guru. Hey Guru.
Even Jhumpa never
cried looking at my face..
What?
Jhumpa, that belly dancer at Turkey.
Even Jhumpa never
cried looking at my face.
Das.
Don't do this.
We have many battles to fight..
I can't do it without
you Ghanshyam brother..
Shyam Saxena!
- Come in. The door is open.
You come out. I want to talk to you.
I can't. I'm in the kitchen.
Come straight, this side.
What kind of a man are you?
Do you even know what you're doing?
Seasoning.. will
you eat? I cook well.
You're insane. Why
are you doing this?
For fame, money? To threaten?
What for?
Do you know five foreign companies
have invested in Shakti Corporation?
Yes, so?
- All five are bogus companies.
All are fake ones.
Can you prove it?
Truth is truth even without proof.
Can you prove it or not?
Good, I can. I can also prove..
..you've joined hands
with ministers to convert..
..non-convertible
debentures into shares.
Shakti Corp's reach is in every..
..department of the government.
Right from..
..the peon to minister,
everyone is part of your family.
You know the rules of the government
even before the public knows.
Using that information,
you play with public money.
Do you have conscious
or you've mortgaged it?
What is this?
Can't you understand on seeing that?
You got married?
Should I have asked
you for that also?
Where is she? Meenu!
Meenu!
- Brother Guru!
Coming.
Meenu!
How come you're here?
What to do?
You just weren't leaving
sister and come to me.
I was forced to get married.
You didn't invite me.
No one had come. Not even grandpa.
He kept his favorites
reporter and kicked me out.
He said that I'd become
a little too independent.
There are 60 crore
people in lndia.
Didn't you get any other
fool to get married to?
But he's a good guy. Have
you come to fight with him?
Yes. I thought I would
say a few things to him.
But on seeing you, my
mouth got shut. - Come.
Hey Shyam. Make sure you love my
Jalkukdi more than you hate me.
Do you need proof for that as well?
What happened? You look very weak.
You've become very fat.
Weak.
- Fat. - Weak. - Fat.
Nothing is going to
Change between us.
When you hear my voice..
..be certain that you're
doing something wrong.
The louder your voice,
the more I'll grow.
I'll leave. Jalkukdi.
Give us our money back.
Yes, come on.
Gurukanth Desai
salutes the Shakti family!
What salute? Answer us!
We don't want a salute. Answer us!
You're angry. Good.
I'm very angry too.
You've asked me a lot of questions.
Now shall I ask you a few questions?
If someone flings
muck at our family..
..throws stones,
what do we do? Tell me.
Do we start fighting
amongst ourselves?
Can a family survive like that?
You ask me why the
papers are writing..
..articles against us.
I'll tell you.
Not the newspaper..
Because we are commoners,
middle class.
And those who are
already rich don't like this.
We want to write our own destiny.
They hate all this.
That is all right.
But do you have a reply to this?
Answer!
What has happened to our money?
What's happened? Answer!
Next year, our turnover
will be hundred crores.
You have stolen and
made us thieves too.
Who was that?
- You're a smuggler!
You steal! Give us back our money!
We will make bigger profits;
I will not give your money.
You are a thief! You wear fancy
suits and drive away in a Mercedes.
We'll be out on the streets!
We want justice!
Down with brother Guru!
- Down with brother Guru!
Give our money back.
Down with brother Guru!
We didn't have money
to white-wash the house.
You said the house
looks best the way it is.
It looks like a home.
Were you telling the truth or
were you trying to pacify me?
Wallet.
You would forget your wallet.
What happened?
I forgot my wallet.
I would climb two steps..
..at a time to come to you.
And you would stand right here.
I won't give it.
Your brother is waiting downstairs.
He will kill me.
You can't die for me?
If I die, who will you fight with?
praise me.
- What?
Say something nice.
You shine brighter than polyester.
Don't talk like a laundryman.
Always talking about polyester.
You're the most
beautiful girl in the locality.
So you look at others?
I don't. Now give it.
Forget it tomorrow as well.
As long as you're with me,
how can I remember anything?
Beast!
How do I look to you?
Your face resembles my husband's.
Do I look like a thief or smuggler?
Neither are you a
thief nor a weakling.
"Why do you trouble me?"
"You tell what you do."
"The king of liars. Tell me."
What if my brother comes?
Guru.
- "Dusk in your eyes."
Always arrives at the wrong time.
"Sometimes dawn in my eyes."
Guru, Guru, Guru.
"Tells a story."
Sister. Where's everybody?
"Open your eyes."
poor guy.
poor thing.
Beast!
"You are unique."
Chilly queen!
Me?
- Who else?
Ready to fight.
Lies. You used to beat poor old me.
When did I hit you?
Here, like this.
Again.
You will lose.
What's happened to you?
Forgotten how to play?
What happened, Guru?
Guru.. Guru.. Guru.
Guru.
I am going down to get an ambulance.
Are you listening?
Just keep breathing.
Ok? Don't be scared?
I'll be right back.
Brother Guru has had
a paralytic stroke.
There was a telex from the p.T. I.
You know what that means? He
can't move the right side at all.
He can neither move his hands,
nor legs. Can't do any work.
He's younger to me by at least
20-25 years. At least 20 years.
An attack at this age? How?
Maybe because of us.
What?
You, me, Swatantra,
everybody is after him.
In fact another article
is coming out tomorrow.
Shall I stop it?
Is what you are printing the truth?
- 100 percent.
Then print it. Why
fear printing the truth?
Which hospital is he in? - Bombay
Hospital. - Bombay Hospital.
Are you going to see him?
No. Why should I?
I won't go there. Why should I?
I won't go.
Grandpa.
Checking to see if he's alive?
He is.
ln two more months, I'll make
him fit enough to fight you.
"I have been awake for long.."
"Let me sleep for some time.."
"There is still some night left.."
"Let morning come.."
"The incomplete dreams that.."
"Couldn't be fulfilled.."
"Once during this sleep.."
"Let those dreams be sowed.."
CT scan.
What is that?
- It is a..
We want to meet Mr. Gurukanth Desai.
You?
Ashok Agarwal, Justice Department.
We have summons for him.
For what?
On the 16th of October, there is
Thapar Commission's final hearing..
..against Shakti Corporation.
But he's asleep.
It is a notice for that.
I have to give it to him.
Look. Yes.. but visiting hours
are over.. please come later.
We have permission
from the High Court.
You will have to appear
before the Thapar Commission..
.. at ten thirty on the
16th of October, 1980.
For the enquiry on any
condition. You have to sign here.
He's asking if you
would like some tea.
Here.
- Only on the copy.
Take this.
- Thank you.
Brother Guru will
see you on the 16th.
please come fully prepared.
Mr. Desai. We are here
to assess if the charges..
..against you and
your company are true.
And if.. - Just a minute please.
- I haven't finished.
And if the charges are found true.
Then this Commission
will recommend suitable..
..punitive action to the government.
Yes, you may speak.
Sir, brother Guru has a request.
Could you please repeat
everything that you just said..
..in Hindi?
We're villagers..
our English is weak.
Both my language and I are right.
Which one would you
like to test, Shri Desai?
What test? You can take our lives..
But whatever you do..
..just do it in Hindi.
Will you be answering.. or will he?
The answers are his,
only the voice is mine.
Is your wife a Shakti employee?
An officer? Or a director?
If you aren't, what are
you doing here? please leave.
Sir I am the owner of Shakti.
lnitial promoter..
..and 50 percent
shareholder in the holding company.
Sir here are the Memorandum
and Articles of Association..
..of the holding company
and the annual returns.
Do you know the meaning of this?
You'll also have to
go to jail with him.
We are 50 percent partners, sir.
Wherever we go, we'll go together.
"This is a critical matter..
..for the people crazy in love."
"The clouds playing..
..with the snow."
Minister of lndustry '68-'72.
Ministry of Finance..
..'73-'78,
Under-Secretary Development..
..Chief Secretary Finance..
Your company has
given all of them land..
..gifts and money. Why?
It has now been proved sir. He
raises his own share prices.
He has a nexus with the brokers.
We have our own broking company.
He has attempted a hostile
takeover of two companies.
The show cause notice
must be given to him, sir.
lmport duty evasion, 12 crore..
for four factories.
Excise duty evasion from '74 to '77.
Total evasion of penalty,
Rs.14 crore..
..27 lakhs, four thousand.
He converts non
convertible debentures.
He then turns these
debentures into shares..
..and clears all his debts.
These conversions
should be disallowed.
The matter is subjudice.
Disallowed! Disallowed!
Mr. Desai, many allegations
have come up against you today.
Do you have a response?
This hearing is in camera only
today. You get it? ln private.
Tomorrow, the press and
the public will be here.
You'd better accept all
the charges today itself.
You are being given an opportunity.
If there is anything
you would like to say..
..in your defense you
may do so now.
I have only one thing to say.
Greetings.
"I love the night.."
"I love the..
..silence of the night."
"I love the night."
"The brightness in the morning..
..and the silent night."
"I love the brightness."
Down with brother Guru!
Hey, let go of me!
I drive a taxi from
Wadala to Churchgate.
I've Shakti shares. I've got my
three daughters married with that.
That's all I wanted to say.
I wanted to thank you.
Don't worry..
because, I am with you.
please be silent.
This commission has heard
all the arguments against..
..and in defense of
Shakti Corporation.
The commission will
declare it's report..
..and recommendations
after the lunch session.
Brother Guru requests your
permission to say something.
He was given an
opportunity yesterday..
..but he just said
greetings and left.
We were told that
your voice is very weak.
I'm a businessman sir. I
spend everything very carefully.
I saved my voice for today.
Beware of what you say.
The public is present..
..what you say could go against you.
Why fear the public..
..I am the public. May I speak?
Five minutes.
May I stand, or do I
need a license for that too?
Enough. Enough.
You say I'm against the law.
Forty years ago, another
man was against the law.
Today we call him Bapu.
In his time slavery was the law..
he wrote a new law..
..our freedom.
I'm not Bapu.
All I know is business..
..and to work hard, and poverty.
I came to Bombay with two shirts..
..a wife and a brother-in-law.
I thought I'll do business.
But when I reached here I saw that
all doors for business were closed.
If they opened, it
was only for the rich.
They were doors made by
the government. Yours.
They either opened
with a bribe or a kick.
I did both.
Where I had to kick, I kicked.
Where you wanted me
to salute, I saluted.
And today you ask why
this man kicks so much..
He salutes too much.
What are you angry about?
My growth or the speed of my growth?
Or is everybody angry because..
I've surpassed the
boundaries of an ordinary villager?
You've made allegations against me..
..excise, custom, income tax,
this tax.. that tax.
When I started business..
..I didn't even know the
meaning of these words.
I fell many times before I learnt.
To save money, I walked 20 kms..
..from pydhonie carrying huge
bales of polyester on my head.
I know the value of money.
If there was money to be made..
..I made it. But
not just for myself.
For my 3 million
shareholders as well.
You have about 3 minutes left.
I don't know how to play golf
and I don't go to horse races..
..but I'm a solid
player in my business.
I know how to make polyester..
..fiber.. chemicals..
of the best quality.
At the cheapest price.
Is that my mistake?
Should I apologize for that?
I roamed around carrying cans
as a petrol pump attendant..
..just like our country goes
to the World Bank begging.
"Give us money we
want to make roads."
Why can't we change our destiny?
Ours and our country's?
You want me to remain a
petrol bunk attendant..
..and our country to beg, forever.
Why can't we reach the top?
Why are we called the third world?
We have as much right to
be a first world country..
..and we can be! We can
reach there at the top.
I've lost a lot reaching here..
I lost this hand. Lousy
thing hangs uselessly!
And by the time this enquiry ends..
..I don't know what
else I will lose..
..my voice, my mind.
But there is one thing you
can never snatch from me.
My courage. I won't lose that.
Because my courage..
..is the common man's courage..
..this country's courage.
All of you want to
stop me, don't you?
I'm not alone.. the whole
country is moving ahead with me.
And neither you nor your laws..
..have the strength
to stop the country.
The doors you want to keep closed,
are opening up..
..we have stuck our
foot through the doors..
..and our feet are very strong.
What enquiry will you
conduct on the nation's progress?
And which enquiry will be
able to stop us? Tell me!
You gave me five minutes.
I've finished talking every
thing in four and a half minutes..
30 seconds profit.
That's business.
If you want to punish
me for that as well..
..go ahead.
Gurukanth Desai is not
scared of punishment.
What do you think? Is
he a genius or a thug?
Both.
Whatever it is, we
can't hang him, can we?
Out of the 29
allegations leveled against..
..Shakti Corporation, 2 are proved.
Shakti Corporation is fined Rs.
6.3 millon and 96,000.
The rest of the
allegations are scrapped.
Gurukanth Desai
salutes the Shakti family.
"Don't dream."
"Dreams never come true."
My father would say.
But I shall dream. We all dreamt.
Dreamt of becoming the..
..biggest company in lndia.
Has our dream come true?
Yes.
- And, do we stop now?
No.
Or do we dream more, courageously?
Yes.
Shall we become the
world's biggest company?
Yes..
Shall we tell the
world that we are coming?
Yes..